Lutfun N. Rahaman

✓ lutfun.begume@gmail.com

Q 347-658-9277

Summary

Innovative Developmental Mathematics Coordinator with an in-depth knowledge of the academic needs of a diverse population of non-traditional students; actively involved in curriculum development and overseeing math program and faculty in a private two-year college, committed to the belief all students can master the math skills that are vital to their success in all careers. Seeking a position in high school to support the math education of students at all levels of learning and ability.

Accomplishments

- Attended seminar and presented a workshop on 'Integrating Technology in the Classroom,' New York College of Technology, CUNY
- Consistently in the top rankings of student evaluations
- Completed ASA Blackboard Faculty Certification Program 2017
- Awarded the most popular instructor award academic year 2017-2018, ASA College, New York
- Developed successful techniques for teaching math at all levels online.

Experience

Mathematics Adjunct Professor

June 2015 – Current

New York City College of Technology, City University of New York, NY

- Teaching Developmental Mathematics, Quantitative Reasoning, College Algebra and Trigonometry, and Pre-calculus.
- Consistently conducting research developments and technological advances in the mathematical and educational fields by reading current literature and participating in professional workshops, seminars, and conferences.
- Invigilating quizzes and final examinations.
- Advising and tutoring at-risk students.

Assistant Professor of Mathematics

August 2005 – Feb 2023

ASA College, New York, NY ***

- Taught Remedial Math, College Algebra, Advanced Mathematics, and Statistics courses using an interactive approach to ensure more excellent learning experiences.
- Trained and mentored new faculty members.
- Created departmental tests, including final exams, class notes, homework assignments, and quizzes.
- Integrated multiple teaching styles to intensify the range of learning.
- Assessed student progress and supported recommendations for further student development
- Presided over departmental meetings with staff.

Teaching Assistant *May 2004 – June 2005*

Math Department at Marquette University, Milwaukee, WI

- Provided tutoring to students in Statistics
 - Taught SPSS computer software

Education

Earned 31 credits in Doctor of Philosophy

September 2002 – May 2004

- Department of Mathematics, University of Wisconsin Milwaukee Milwaukee, WI
- **MS** in Mathematics

January 2000 - May 2002

- Department of Mathematics, Western Illinois University Macomb, IL
- Department of Mathematics, University of Dhaka Dhaka, Bangladesh

January 88 – Dec 1994

Skills

- Asynchronous and Synchronous instruction
- Creative lesson planning

BS in Mathematics

- Differentiative instruction techniques
- **Technology Proficiency**
- Collaborative teamwork capabilities
- Familiarity with virtual interactive and education system

Virtual Teaching Skill

- Zoom, Webex (Instruction), Blackboard (Co-ordination), Notability, one note(Student-Teacher Virtual Interaction
- MyLab Math, WeBWork, WebAssign, ALEKs (Assignments, Test)

Languages:

SPSS, Maple, COBOL, Mat lab